import 'package:quiz_app/model/question_model.dart';

const List<Question> questionList = [
  Question(
    question: '1. Who is the smartest marine creature?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Shark',
      'b) Dolphin',
      'c) Tuna ',
      'd) salmon',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '2. In which city is the famous Big Ben located?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) New York',
      'b) Los Angeles',
      'c) London',
      'd) Cardiff',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '3.How many teeth do cats have?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) 38',
      'b) 40',
      'c) 44',
      'd) 34',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '4. What is the longest river in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Danube',
      'b) Amazon',
      'c) Mississippi',
      'd) Nile',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '5. How many hearts does an octopus have?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) 2',
      'b) 4',
      'c) 6',
      'd) 3',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '6. What is the smallest planet in our solar system?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) Venus',
      'b) Mars',
      'c) Earth',
      'd) Mercury',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '7. What is the fastest bird in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Golden eagle',
      'b) Peregrine falcon',
      'c) Frigatebird',
      'd) Gyrfalcon',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '8. What is the highest mountain in the world?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Mont Blanc',
      'b)Kilimanjaro ',
      'c) Everest',
      'd) Aconcagua',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question:
        '9. What is the name of the famous painting by Leonardo da Vinci that depicts a woman?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Starry Night',
      'b) Mona Lisa',
      'c) The Last Supper',
      'd)The Persistence of Memory ',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '10.Which countries have the highest life expectancy?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Monaco',
      'b) Hong Kong ',
      'c) Japan	',
      'd) Singapore',
    ],
  ),
];
